Youngmin Kim

youngmnk@umich.edu I +1 (734) 800 6767 I https://kimyoungmin.me

Talented Interaction designer with 4+ years of experience at startup. I sort through the clutter, find the best route and consider all factors that might affect the circumstance. I am an optimistic survivor and enjoy integrating my design with the unique qualities of each person in a team.

SKILLS

UX METHOD

Low / High Fidelity Design Interaction Prototyping User Interface Design Contextual Inquiry Persona & Scenario Storyboarding Usability Testing Survey / Interview Affinity Wall

Cognitive Walkthrough

Wireframing

SOFTWARE

Sketch
Adobe XD
Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
Premiere Pro
After Effect
Invision Studio
Balsamiq
Zeplin
Origami

PROGRAMMING

HTML+CSS PYTHON

Axure RP

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (FLUENT) KOREAN (NATIVE)

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, School of Information

Master of Science in Information

Sep 2018 - April 2020 I Ann Arbor, MI

Focusing on User Experience and Human Centered Interaction.

Handong Global University

BA in Visual Communication Design, BS in Products Design, BA in Management

Feb 2009 - Feb 2015 I Pohang, Korea

GPA: 3.75/4.5

Triple-majored, primarily interested in UX/UI design, graphic design, and infographic design.

Received a scholarship for academic excellence in 2013.

Joined acappella group 'Madrigal' and marketing society 'COLORZ.'

EXPERIENCE

University Of Michigan ITS - Media Management Assistant

October 2018 - Present I Ann Arbor, MI

Working for ITS Teaching and Learning team focusing on a user interface (UI) upgrade of MiVideo space, which is a platform for video lectures. Supporting current customers directly in transition to the new UI.

SBCN - UX researcher

Apr 2018 - July 2018 | Seoul, Korea

Coordinated the Bitcoin team focusing on user experience design for new service, BitMEX, which aims at increase customers' investments by analyzing the movement of money flow with artificial intelligence (AI).

Merlot Lab - UX/UI designer

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018 | Seoul, Korea

Coordinated an IoT application 'Merlot Home' for new light bulb 'Lean bulb'. Executed UX and UI design of the app that aims at connecting and controlling electronic products at home with the smartphone.

Cardoc Inc. - UX/UI designer

Jan 2015 - June 2017 I Seoul, Korea

Redesigned and restructured 'Cardoc' app (Android & iOS), which is primarily a car repair service including maintenance and car wash. Designed an Android application 'Cardoc Partners' for partner repair shops to improve their business process. Designed web-based landing pages for newly-launched services.

Mostly collaborated with project managers, developers, and marketing staff. Maximized productivity using Github desktop and Zeplin for sharing sources with developers and boosted efficiency in communication using Axure and InVision with product managers.

X4 Design Branding - Graphic designer, Intern

Jul 2013 - Aug 2013 I Seoul, Korea

Researched tourists who have visited Gangwon Province and analyzed data of travel trend of this region. Based on that, designed tourism icon and Infographic map by putting complicated historical or legendary story into one implicit image. Developed a brand identity for the second-hand bookstore as well.

Hidden J Grace - Design manager

Dec 2012 - May 2013 | Seoul, Korea

Built strategies for starting 'social enterprise company' which gives stable job opportunities to socially vulnerable classes. Designed brand identity and business cards. Worked on Marketing contents for a Facebook page or its official website. Designed brochures for promoting the service.